Same planet. New scum.
Men in Black II is a action, comedy, science fiction
film directed by Barry Sonnenfeld.
Kay and Jay reunite to provide our best, last and only line of defense against a sinister seductress who levels the toughest
challenge yet to the MIB's untarnished mission statement – protecting Earth from the scum of the universe.
It's been four years since the alien-seeking agents averted an
intergalactic disaster of epic proportions.
Now it's a race against the clock as Jay must convince Kay – who not only has absolutely no memory of his time spent with the MIB, but is also the only
living person left with the expertise to save the galaxy – to reunite with the MIB before the earth submits to ultimate destruction.
Kay, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Jay, played by Will Smith.
Zed, played by Rip Torn.
Serleena, played by Lara Flynn Boyle.
Scrad / Charlie, played by Johnny Knoxville.
Laura Vasquez, played by Rosario Dawson.
Men in Black II (stylized as MIIB) is a 2002 American science fiction action comedy film based
on the Marvel Comics series of a similar name based on the conspiracy theory.
Produced by Columbia Pictures and Amblin Entertainment in association with MacDonald/Parkes Productions, and distributed by Sony
Pictures Releasing, it is the sequel to Men in Black (1997) and the second installment in the Men in Black film series.
The film was directed by Barry Sonnenfeld from a screenplay by Robert Gordon and Barry Fanaro, and it stars Tommy Lee Jones and
Will Smith, with Lara Flynn Boyle, Johnny Knoxville, Rosario Dawson, Tony Shalhoub, and Rip Torn in supporting roles.
It also featured Michael Jackson's last feature film
appearance before his death in 2009.
In the film, the emergence of an alien threat reunites Kevin Brown / Agent
K (Jones) and James Darrell Edwards III / Agent J (Smith).
Development for a sequel film began following the box office success of the original; Jones, Smith, and
Sonnenfeld's returns were confirmed by 2001, and David Koepp was initially hired to write the screenplay.
Koepp then left production to work on Spider-Man (2002) and was replaced
with Gordon, who developed the script and story further.
Fanaro was later brought in to perform some final
rewrites to Gordon's treatment.
Principal photography began on June 11, 2001, and lasted until that September, taking place primarily in New York
City; filming was delayed and several scenes were reworked following the September 11 attacks that month.
The film's soundtrack contained the theme song "Black Suits
Comin' (Nod Ya Head)", performed by Smith.
Aside from this song, composer Danny Elfman, who scored the
first film, returned to compose its sequel.
Men in Black II premiered at Mann Village Theater in Westwood, Los Angeles on June 26,
2002, and was theatrically released in the United States on July 3.
It received generally mixed reviews from critics, who deemed it inferior to its
predecessor, but praised Jones's and Smith's performances and action sequences.
Nonetheless, it was a financial success, grossing $445.1 million
worldwide and becoming the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2002.
Its sequel, Men in Black 3, was released in 2012 to an
improved critical and commercial response.
The film explores themes of new york city, space marine,
saving the world, flying saucer, undercover.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.